Now you have learned to think inside the Flexbox,
تعلمنا طريقة عمل «فليكس بوكس»
using the box model.
واستخدام نموذج الصندوق المرن،
With so many boxes there's so much to store.
حيث يتيح وجود هذا العدد الكبير من الصناديق حفظ وتخزين الكثير.
In this lesson, we learned how the display property, Flex,
في هذا الدرس، تعلمنا كيفية استخدام خاصية العرض «فليكس»
on a container element can be used to control
على عنصر الحاوية للتحكم
the distribution and alignment of elements inside of it.
بتوزيع ومحاذاة العناصر بداخلها.
We learned to control the flex flow with flex direction column or row.
تعلمنا التحكم بالتدفق من خلال ضبط الاتجاه المرن إلى عمود أو صف.
We learned how to justify and align content along the main and cross axes.
وتعلمنا ضبط ومحاذاة المحتوى على طول المحور الرئيسي والمتعامد عليه.
We also learned how a flex container can expand to
تعلّمنا كذلك كيف تتوسع الحاوية المرنة
fit the items inside of it and to prevent overflow.
لاستيعاب العناصر بداخلها.
Unlike many other CSS properties,
وبخلاف العديد من خصائص CSS الأخرى،
Flex has a main container and then inside of it it has elements that we call items.
تتمتع فليكس بوجود حاوية رئيسية وبداخلها توجد عناصر نسميها عناصر فرعية.
Some CSS Flex properties are used only on the parent and others are used on the items.
يقتصر استخدام بعض خصائص CSS المرنة على العنصر الأصل وتقتصر الخصائص الأخرى على العناصر الفرعية.
Now, I wish you great luck using Flexbox in the wild.
أتمنى لكم التوفيق في استخدام فليكس بوكس بأنفسكم.
It's one of those things that I think now that you have learned it,
فهو أحد الأمور التي أعتقد أن تعلمها يتيح لكم
you'll start to recognize it at a lot of the different developing places you go.
التعرف إلى استخدامها في العديد من المواقع التي تزورونها.
Flex is constantly used for web development and it's
تستخدم فليكس باستمرار في تطوير الويب وهي
well worth your time to learn how you can align,
أداة تستحق تخصيص وقت لتعلمها ومعرفة كيفية محاذاة
distribute, and set up a set of elements just in the way that you want. Good luck.
وتوزيع وضبط مجموعة من العناصر بالطريقة التي تريد. أتمنى لكم التوفيق.